Guide to the Richard Powell Papers, 1960-2011 RL.01043
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Richard Powell papers
1960-2011
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.01043
40 Linear Feet
Richard J. Powell is the John Spencer Bassett Professor of Art and Art History at Duke University, where he has taught since 1989. The Richard Powell Papers date from 1960 to 2011 and document Powell's career as a prominent scholar of African and Afro-American art and as professor of art history at Duke University. Materials originate from Powell's student years, travels, research, and work at various cultural institutions, including Duke University, the Smithsonian Museum of American Art, and the Washington Project for the Arts. There is extensive material on Powell's books, exhibitions, and other professional activities.
30,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Audiovisual materials in Box 58 are CLOSED until use copies can be made.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Richard Powell Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2011.
Biographical Note
Richard J. Powell is the John Spencer Bassett Professor of Art, Art History & Visual Studies at Duke University. Powell received a B.A. from Morehouse University in 1975, a M.F.A. in Printmaking from Howard University in 1977, a M.A. in Afro-American Studies from Yale University in 1982, and a Ph.D. in the History of Art, also from Yale University, in 1988. Powell was the Director of Programs at the Washington Project for the Arts before arriving at Duke in 1989. He has written numerous books and articles on African and Afro-American art and is interested in theories of race and representation in the African diaspora as well as media arts and conceptualizations of the "folk" in world art and culture. Powell has received many prestigious fellowships and grants from organizations such as the Ford Foundation and the Fulbright Program.
Collection Overview
The Richard J. Powell Papers document Powell's career as a prominent scholar of African and Afro-American art. Materials in the collection date from 1960 to 2011, with the bulk being from 1975 to 2011, and document most aspects of Powell's career, beginning with his student years and including his travels, research, and work at several major cultural institutions, including Duke University, the Smithsonian Museum of American Art, and the Washington Project for the Arts.
The Name Files Series contains Powell's incoming and outgoing correspondence with well-known artists, such as Adrian Piper, Martin Puryear, and Carrie Mae Weems, as well as curators, professors, and other professionals with whom Powell collaborated on exhibitions, books, and other projects. The series also contains personal letters and postcards.
The Subjects Series includes texts, newspaper articles, exhibition publicity, and notes on a range of subjects including major art museums and galleries, publications, courses taught at Duke University, and diverse research topics including the Kongo and Jazz, among others. Many of the subject files also contain Powell's notes and correspondence.
The Books Series contains materials pertaining to the research, writing, and publication of Richard J. Powell's various books: Cutting a Figure: Fashioning Black Portraiture of 2008; Homecoming: The Art and Life of William H. Johnson of 1991 along with a related exhibition at the Smithsonian National Museum of American Art; and Black Art & Culture in the 20th Century of 1997.
The Reference Images Series comprises Powell's reference photographs, photocopies, and other reproductions of works of art.
The Exhibitions Series includes information on exhibitions curated by Powell, including Back to Black: Art, Cinema, and the Racial Imaginary (2005), To Conserve a Legacy: American Art from Historically Black Colleges and Universities (1999), Circle Dance: The Art of John T. Scott (2005), Barkley L. Hendricks materials (2000-2008), Rhapsodies in Black (1995-1997), The Blues Aesthetic (1996-1998) and Conjuring Bearden (2004-2006).
The Donyale Luna Project Series contains Powell's research on African-American 1960s supermodel Donyale Luna, to whose life and portraiture he dedicated a chapter in his 2008 book, Cutting a Figure: Fashioning Black Portraiture.
The Printed Materials Series contains flyers, booklets, postcards, pamphlets, posters, periodicals, and catalogues from a variety of American and international museums and art galleries.
The Personal and Early Papers Series documents Powell's childhood, collegiate and graduate education, as well as his early years as a member of the Duke University faculty.
The Articles and Lectures by Powell Series comprises articles, graduate research papers from Yale and Howard Universities, and lectures.
The Photographs Series contains images of Powell and others arranged into subsections: Professional, Personal, Portraits, and Artists, Writers, Curators, etc. Among these photographs are images of Powell with Hillary Rodham Clinton, Jesse Jackson, and Spike Lee.
The Works of Art Series includes art made by Richard J. Powell and others, and are mostly prints. The Art Subseries is organized by artist.
Finally, the Audio Series contains cassette tapes documenting interviews with artists, such as Jacob Lawrence and Martin Puryear, and events at the National Center for the Humanities and the Museum of Modern Art.
- Name Files, 1980-2009, 16 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains correspondence and related material, such as photographs, slides, negatives, transparencies, exhibition materials, articles, newspapers, cards, and notes, which Powell filed by individual name, usually the correspondent, but sometimes the subject. Powell exchanged letters and cards with many notable twentieth-century artists, including Adrian Piper, Martin Puryear, Carrie Mae Weems, and E.H. Sorrells-Adewale, as well as a variety of prominent professors and curators at such places as the National Gallery of Art, the Corcoran Gallery, Philadelphia Museum of Art, and Yale University. These materials, dating from approximately 1980 to 2009, relate to Powell's work on publications, exhibitions, professional development and appointments, as well as his personal friendships and connections. The series includes research notes and plans for exhibitions on the art of Romare Bearden and William H. Johnson, among others, and preparatory work for Dr. Powell's books Cutting a Figure: Fashioning Black Portraiture and Black Art: A Cultural History, topics which are also documented extensively in other parts of the collection.
  Arrangement note
  The materials in the Name Files Series are organized alphabetically by correspondent's last name.
  - Abele, Julian (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Cliff (Box 1)
  - Adams, John Henry (Box 1)
  - Allen, William Duncan (Box 1)
  - Alston, Peg (Box 1)
  - Alvarez, Candida (Box 1)
  - Amos, Emma (Box 1)
  - Anderson, T.J. (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Penny (Box 1)
  - Archer, John R. (Box 1)
  - Archer-Straw, Petrine (Box 1)
  - Austin, Ramona (Box 1)
  - Ayon, Belkis (Box 2)
  - Baartman, Sartje (Box 2)
  - Baily, David A. (Box 2)
  - Banjo, Casper (Box 2)
  - Barboza, Anthony (Box 2)
  - Barnes, Ernie (Box 2)
  - Basquiat, Jean-Michel (Box 2)
  - Beard, Derrick (Box 2)
  - Bearden, Romare (Box 2)
  - Bell, Roseann Pope (Box 2)
  - Bettelhelm, Judith (Box 2)
  - Bey, Dawoud (Box 2)
  - Biggers, John (Box 3)
  - Billops, Camille (Box 3)
  - Birch, Willie (Box 3)
  - Blier, Suzanne (Box 3)
  - Blythe, David Gilmour (Box 3)
  - Boghassian, Skunder (Box 3)
  - Bondo, Sigrid (Box 3)
  - Booker, Chakaia (Box 3)
  - Boone, Sylvia (Box 3)
  - Bowens, Kabuya (Box 3)
  - Bowling, Frank (Box 3)
  - Bowser, David B. (Box 3)
  - Boyce, Sonia (Box 3)
  - Breeskin, Adelyn (Box 3)
  - Brown, David (Box 3)
  - Brown, Frederick (Box 3)
  - Brown, Henry (Box 3)
  - Brown, James (Box 3)
  - Brown, J. Carter (Box 3)
  - Brown, Joseph A. (Box 3)
  - Brown, Rae Linda (Box 3)
  - Buchanan, Beverly (Box 3)
  - Bundles, A'Lelia (Box 3)
  - Burke, Selma (Box 3)
  - Burkett, Randal (Box 3)
  - Burns, Ronald (Box 3)
  - Burroughs, Margaret (Box 3)
  - Burrows, Stephen (Box 3)
  - Butcher, Ras Ishi (Box 3)
  - Byrd, Rudolph (Box 3)
  - Byrne, E. Blake (Box 3)
  - Calfritz, Peggy Cooper (Box 4)
  - Calo, Mary Ann (Box 4)
  - Camp, Sokari Douglas (Box 4)
  - Carter, Charlotte (Box 4)
  - Carter, Nanette (Box 4)
  - Catlett, Elizabeth (Box 4)
  - Cazzaniga, Luigi (Box 4)
  - Chandler, Dana (Box 4)
  - Chicago, Judy (Box 4)
  - Chong, Albert (Box 4)
  - Chung, Y. David (Box 4)
  - Clark, Ed (Box 4)
  - Clonney, James G. (Box 4)
  - Coe, Sue (Box 4)
  - Coleman, Ornette (Box 4)
  - Concholar, Dan (Box 4)
  - Conwill, Houston (Box 4)
  - Cooper, William Arthur (Box 4)
  - Cornaille, Roger (Box 4)
  - Cortez, Diego (Box 4)
  - Cortor, Eldzier (Box 4)
  - Cowans, Adger (Box 4)
  - Cox, Renee (Box 4)
  - Crite, Allan Rohan (Box 4)
  - Crooper, Elizabeth (Box 4)
  - Cruz, Emilio (Box 4)
  - Cozier, Christopher (Box 4)
  - Cummings, Michael (Box 4)
  - Cuno, James (Box 4)
  - Dalton, Karen (Box 4)
  - Davis, Angela (Box 4)
  - Davis, Ulysses (Box 4)
  - Dawson, Daniel (Box 4)
  - Day, F. Holland (Box 4)
  - Day, Thomas (Box 4)
  - Debela, Archameleh (Box 4)
  - DeCarava, Roy (Box 5)
  - Delaney, Beauford (Box 5)
  - Delsarte, Louis (Box 5)
  - Denney, Alice (Box 5)
  - DePillars, Murray (Box 5)
  - DiLucci, Mario (Box 5)
  - DJ Spooky (Box 5)
  - Donaldson, Jeff (Box 5)
  - Douglass, Frederick (Box 5)
  - Douglas, Stan (Box 5)
  - Douglas, Aaron (Box 5)
  - Dowd, Jerome (Box 5)
  - Dowell, John E. (Box 5)
  - Driskell, David (Box 5)
  - Dunham, Katherine (Box 5)
  - Dunkley, Tina (Box 6)
  - Duval-Carrié, Edouard (Box 6)
  - Eakins, Thomas (Box 6)
  - Early, Gerald (Box 6)
  - Eco, Umberto (Box 6)
  - Egonu, Uzo (Box 6)
  - Ellison, Ralph (Box 6)
  - Evans-Tibbs Gallery (Box 6)
  - Fabio, Cheryl (Box 6)
  - Fabre, Michel (Box 6)
  - Fenn, Lil (Box 6)
  - Ferguson, Gerard (Box 6)
  - Ferrer, Rafael (Box 6)
  - Finley, Cheryl (Box 6)
  - Fitzpatrick, Sandy & Jim (Box 6)
  - Fleming, Sherman (Box 6)
  - Frank, Robert (Box 6)
  - Franklin, John Hope (Box 6)
  - Freeman, James E. (Box 6)
  - Freeman, Roland (Box 6)
  - Gaither, Edmund Barry (Box 6)
  - Galembo, Phyllis (Box 6)
  - Garrido-Saavedra, Maria (Box 6)
  - Gates, Henry Louis (Skip) (Box 6)
  - Gayles, Gloria (Box 6)
  - Gentry, Herbert (Box 6)
  - Germina, Halle (Box 6)
  - Gilliam, Sam (Box 6)
  - Girand, Camille (Box 6)
  - Glamann, Kirsten (Box 6)
  - Gomez, Edward (Box 6)
  - Gonde, Jean-Paul (Box 6)
  - Graham, John (Box 6)
  - Grama, Teresa (Box 6)
  - Gray, Ted (Box 7)
  - Greaves, Stanley (Box 7)
  - Green, Renée (Box 7)
  - Gregory, Joy (Box 7)
  - Griffith, Francis (Box 7)
  - Guerrila Girls (Box 7)
  - Hachman, Aden (Box 7)
  - Hagedorn, Jessica (Box 7)
  - Hammons, David (Box 7)
  - Hampton, James (Box 7)
  - Haraway, Donna (Box 7)
  - Hardy, Jeremiah (Box 7)
  - Harleston, Edwin A. (Box 7)
  - Harper, Ves (Box 7)
  - Harris, Lyle (Box 7)
  - Harris, Michael (Box 7)
  - Harris, Thomas Allen (Box 7)
  - Thomas-Harrington, Ollie (Box 7)
  - Hayden, Palmer (Box 7)
  - Henderson, Mae (Box 7)
  - Hendricks, Barkley (Box 7)
  - Herriman, George (Box 7)
  - Herskavites, Melville (Box 7)
  - Hines, Felrath (Box 7)
  - Homes, Jacqui (Box 7)
  - Homer, Winslow (Box 7)
  - Hooks, Bell (Box 7)
  - Hooks, Earl (Box 7)
  - Honeywood, Varnette (Box 7)
  - Hughes, Langston (Box 7)
  - Humphrey, Margo (Box 8)
  - Hunt, Richard (Box 8)
  - Hunter, Clementine (Box 8)
  - Harston, Zora Neale (Box 8)
  - Mr. Imagination (Box 8)
  - Jackson, David Earl (Box 8)
  - Jackson, Homer (Box 8)
  - Jackson, Harlan (Box 8)
  - Jackson, Rev. Joseph Harrison (Box 8)
  - Jackson, Michael (Box 8)
  - Jackson, Samuel L. (Box 8)
  - Jackson-Jarvis, Martha (Box 8)
  - Janniot, Alfred (Box 8)
  - Jantjes, Gavin (Box 8)
  - Jarrell, Wadsworth (Box 8)
  - Jeffries, Roz (Box 8)
  - Jenkins, Ella (Box 8)
  - Johnson, James Weldon (Box 8)
  - Johnson, Joshua (Box 8)
  - Johnson, Robert (Box 8)
  - Johnson, Sargent (Box 8)
  - Johnston, Frances Benjamin (Box 8)
  - Jones, Ben (Box 8)
  - Jones, Bill T. (Box 8)
  - Jones, Gary (Box 8)
  - Jones, Grace (Box 8)
  - Jones, John (Box 9)
  - Jones, Kellie (Box 9)
  - Jones, Lois Mailou (Box 9)
  - Jones, Patricia (Box 9)
  - Jones, Phillip Mallory (Box 9)
  - Jones, Stephen (Box 9)
  - Kamala, Madame (Box 9)
  - Kennedy, Joe (Box 9)
  - Khalil, Mohammed (Box 9)
  - King, Susan (Box 9)
  - Koons, Jeff (Box 9)
  - Kutzinski, Vera (Box 9)
  - LaChapelle, David (Box 9)
  - Lam, Wilfredo (Box 9)
  - Lawrence, Jacob (Box 9)
  - Lawrence-Lightfoot, Sara (Box 9)
  - Lee, Glover (Box 9)
  - Lee, Spike (Box 9)
  - Lewis, Edmonia (Box 10)
  - Lewis, Norman (Box 10)
  - Ligon, Glenn (Box 10)
  - Liking, Werewere (Box 10)
  - Lindsay, Vachel (Box 10)
  - Logan, Juan (Box 10)
  - Long, Bert (Box 10)
  - Long, Richard A. (Box 10)
  - Lorde, Audre (Box 10)
  - Lovell, Whitfield (Box 10)
  - Loving, Al (Box 10)
  - Lyons, John (Box 10)
  - McGruder, Aaron (Box 10)
  - McIver, Beverly (Box 10)
  - McQueen, Steve (Box 10)
  - Malcolm X (Box 10)
  - Marshall, Kerry James (Box 10)
  - Matthews, Nancy (Box 10)
  - Medici, Guilia de (Box 10)
  - Mercer, Kobena (Box 10)
  - Miller, Angela (Box 10)
  - Miller, E. Ethelbert (Box 10)
  - Mills, Lev (Box 10)
  - Miner, Leigh Richmond (Box 10)
  - Mingo, George (Box 10)
  - Moja, Januwa (Box 11)
  - Money Man (Box 11)
  - Moody, Ronald (Box 11)
  - Moore, John L. (Box 11)
  - Moore, Philip (Box 11)
  - Naylor, Gloria (Box 11)
  - Motley, Archie (Box 11)
  - Mount, William Sidney (Box 11)
  - Naylor, Gloria (Box 11)
  - Neal, Isobel (Box 11)
  - Nengudi, Senga (Box 11)
  - Ofili, Chris (Box 11)
  - O'Grady, Lorraine (Box 11)
  - Onobrakpeya, Bruce (Box 11)
  - Outtara (Box 11)
  - Panzer, Mary (Box 11)
  - Parker, Jim (Box 11)
  - Parkerson, Michelle (Box 11)
  - Payne, Leslie (Box 11)
  - Pendergraft, Norman (Box 11)
  - Perjovschi, Dan &Lia (Box 11)
  - Phillips, Basil (Box 11)
  - Phillips, James (Box 11)
  - Phokela, Johannes (Box 11)
  - Picton, John (Box 11)
  - Pindell, Howardena (Box 11)
  - Piper, Adrian (Box 11)
  - Piper, Keith (Box 12)
  - Pippen, Horace (Box 12)
  - Polk, P.H. (Box 12)
  - Pollard, Ingrid (Box 12)
  - Porter, Connie (Box 12)
  - Powers, Harriet (Box 12)
  - Prigoff, James (Box 12)
  - Prown, Jules D. (Box 12)
  - Purvis, Robert (Box 12)
  - Puryear, Martin (Box 12)
  - Ramos-Blanco, Teodoro (Box 12)
  - Rampersad, Arnold (Box 12)
  - Rand, Archie (Box 12)
  - Ray, Man (Box 12)
  - Reid, Calvin (Box 12)
  - Reid, Vernon (Box 12)
  - Reynolds, Jock (Box 12)
  - Riggs, Marlon (Box 12)
  - Riggs, Robert (Box 12)
  - Ringgold, Faith (Box 12)
  - Rivers, Bill (Box 12)
  - Robinson, John (Box 12)
  - Robinson, Jontyle (Box 12)
  - Rogers, Paul (Box 12)
  - Rooy, Felix de (Box 12)
  - Rosenberg, Harold (Box 12)
  - Saar, Alison (Box 12)
  - Saar, Betye (Box 12)
  - Saar, Lezley (Box 12)
  - Samba, Cheri (Box 12)
  - Saunders, Raymond (Box 12)
  - Savain, Petion (Box 12)
  - Scott, Joyce J. (Box 12)
  - Scott, William Edouard (Box 12)
  - Sebree, Charles (Box 12)
  - Sekoto, Gerard (Box 13)
  - Sekula, Allan (Box 13)
  - Seman, Jim &Mary (Box 13)
  - Shockley, Ann Allen (Box 13)
  - Shonibare, Yinka (Box 13)
  - Simmons, Gary (Box 13)
  - Sims, Lowery (Box 13)
  - Simpson, Coreen (Box 13)
  - Smalls, James (Box 13)
  - Smith, Terence (Box 13)
  - Smith, Vincent (Box 13)
  - Smith, Mieke (Box 13)
  - Snowden, Sylvia (Box 13)
  - Sonis, Dick &Nancy (Box 13)
  - Sorrells-Adewale, E.H. (Box 13)
  - Soyinka, Wole (Box 13)
  - Stallybrass, Peter & Allon White (Box 13)
  - Steinbaum, Bernice (Box 13)
  - Stern, Irma (Box 13)
  - Stewart, Charles (Box 13)
  - Stewart, Frank (Box 13)
  - Stone III, Charles S. (Box 13)
  - Stone-Miller, Rebecca (Box 13)
  - Stout, Renée (Box 13)
  - Sulter, Maud (Box 13)
  - Talia, Halima (Box 13)
  - Tam, Joseph (Box 13)
  - Tanner, Henry Ossawa (Box 14)
  - Tate, Greg (Box 14)
  - Taylor, Prentiss (Box 14)
  - Telemaque, Hervé (Box 14)
  - Thomas, Alma (Box 14)
  - Thomas, Clarence (Box 14)
  - Thompson, Bob (Box 14)
  - Thompson, Phyllis (Box 14)
  - Thompson, Robert Farris (Box 14)
  - Thurlow Jr., Evans Tibbs (Box 14)
  - Toussaint, Pierre (Box 14)
  - Traylor, Bill (Box 14)
  - Truth, Sojourner (Box 14)
  - Tucker, Mark (Box 14)
  - Tuggar, Fatimah (Box 14)
  - Turner, Patricia (Box 14)
  - Turner, Steve (Box 14)
  - Van Vechten, Carl (Box 14)
  - Vann, Barry (Box 14)
  - Walker, Alice (Box 14)
  - Walker, Ken (Box 14)
  - Walker, Kara (Box 14)
  - Watson, Osmond (Box 15)
  - Webb, Clifton (Box 15)
  - Webb, Frank (Box 15)
  - Weems, Carrie Mae (Box 15)
  - Wells, James L. (Box 15)
  - White, Charles (Box 15)
  - Whitten, Jack (Box 15)
  - Williams, Bert (Box 15)
  - Williams, Kenny Jackson (Box 15)
  - Williams, Paul (Box 15)
  - Williams, William T. (Box 15)
  - Williamson, Sue (Box 15)
  - Willis, Deborah (Box 15)
  - Wilson, Fred (Box 16)
  - Wilson, Gloria (Box 16)
  - Wilson, Judith (Box 16)
  - Woo, John (Box 16)
  - Wood, Debbie (Box 16)
  - Wood, James (Box 16)
  - Wood, Thomas Waterman (Box 16)
  - Woodruff, Hale (Box 16)
  - Wright, Beryl (Box 16)
  - Wright, Richard (Box 16)
  - Xu, Bing (Box 16)
  - Yearwood, Gladstone (Box 16)
  - Yoakum, Joseph (Box 16)
  - Zuschlag, Nancy (Box 16)
- Subject Files, 1977-2010, 4 boxes
  The series includes texts, newspaper articles, exhibition publicity, notes, and letters dating from approximately 1977 to 2010, which Powell maintained by topic or, in the case of cultural institutions, organizational name. The series includes correspondence with museums, such as the Smithsonian African-American Museum, the New Orleans Museum of Art, and the Addison Gallery of American Art, as well as numerous art galleries in New York and London. There are also materials regarding Powell's publications in the Art Bulletin, his work on various exhibitions, research trips to Barbados, and printed texts that Powell used in his Duke classes, many of which he annotated.
  These materials are arranged alphabetically by subject or organizational name.
  - Abstraction (Box 16)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art (Box 16)
  - African Art (Box 16)
  - African-American Art Bibliography (Box 16)
  - African &Afro-American Studies at Duke (Box 16)
  - American Architecture (Box 16)
  - Art Bulletin (Box 17)
  - Autograph, London (Box 17)
  - B.E.T., Inc. (Box 17)
  - Barbados Project (Box 17)
  - Black Atlantic Notes (Box 17)
  - Black Ecuador (Box 17)
  - Black Feminism (Box 17)
  - Black Male (Box 17)
  - Black Music (Box 17)
  - Black Orpheus (Box 17)
  - Black Photography (Box 17)
  - Blues (Box 17)
  - Chicago Historical Society (Box 17)
  - Civil Rights (Box 17)
  - Contemporary African Art (Box 17)
  - Dance (Box 17)
  - Detroit Institute of Art (Box 17)
  - Drums (Box 17)
  - Duke Architecture (Box 17)
  - Ejagham (Box 17)
  - Encyclopedia of African American Art (Box 17)
  - Fang (Box 17)
  - Folk Art (Box 18)
  - FON (Box 18)
  - Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper (Box 18)
  - From the Potomac to the Anacostia: Art &Ideology… (Box 18)
  - Godfather (Box 18)
  - Hampton University (Box 18)
  - Hands (Box 18)
  - Harlem Renaissance (Box 18)
  - Harvard Museums (Box 18)
  - Hayward Gallery (Box 18)
  - Hottentott Venus (Box 18)
  - Humanities West (Box 18)
  - Institute of Contemporary Arts, London (Box 18)
  - Igbo (Box 18)
  - Institute of International Visual Arts, London (Box 18)
  - Insiders &Outsiders (Box 18)
  - Jamaica, Spring 1995 (Box 18)
  - Jazz (Box 18)
  - Jazz Study Group, Columbia University (Box 18)
  - Jenne (Box 18)
  - Johannesburg Biennale (Box 18)
  - Just Above Midtown Gallery (Box 18)
  - Kenkeleba Gallery (Box 18)
  - Kongo (Box 18)
  - Liberia, West Africa (Box 18)
  - Ludwig Foundation, Cuba (Box 18)
  - Lynching in Art (Box 18)
  - Masks/Masquerade (Box 18)
  - Mende (Box 18)
  - Morehouse College (Box 19)
  - Music Theory (Box 19)
  - Multi-Culturalism (Box 19)
  - Muse Gallery (Box 19)
  - Narcissus (Box 19)
  - New Orleans Museum of Art (Box 19)
  - "Nigger Drawings" (Box 19)
  - Paris Conference: A Visual Arts Encounter: African-Americans &Europe (Box 19)
  - Photography (Box 19)
  - Portraiture Bibliography (Box 19)
  - Princeton University (Box 19)
  - Race &Rep. (Box 19)
  - Rap-as-Art (Box 19)
  - Rhino Records (Box 19)
  - Rizzoli (Box 19)
  - Sacks Fine Art Inc. (Box 19)
  - Satre's Black Orpheus (Box 19)
  - Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture (Box 19)
  - Second Line, New Orleans (Box 19)
  - Slave Preferences in U.S. (Box 19)
  - Slavery (Box 19)
  - Smithsonian Institute: African American Museum (Box 19)
  - Stereotype Imagery (Box 20)
  - Studio Museum, Harlem (Box 20)
  - Suriname (Box 20)
  - Theory (Box 20)
  - University of California Press (Box 20)
  - Visual Memory Training (Box 20)
  - Washington Project for the Arts (Box 20)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art (Box 20)
  - Yale Repertory Theater (Box 20)
- Printed Materials, 1980-2011, 9 boxes
  The Printed Materials series contains exhibition ephemera and catalogues from a variety of museums and galleries along with periodicals.
  The series is divided into three subseries: Exhibitions, Periodicals, and Posters.
  - Exhibitions
    This subseries contains exhibition flyers, booklets, postcards, and pamphlets as well as some small catalogues from a variety of American and international museums and art galleries.
    Documents are arranged alphabetically by the artist's last name (for solo exhibitions) or by exhibition title (for group show).
    - A-AD (Box 30)
      Includes materials for Terry Adkins
    - AF (Box 30)
      Includes materials on African American art
    - AG-AL (Box 30)
      Includes materials on Candida Alvarez
    - AM-AN (Box 31)
      Includes materials on Benny Anderson
    - AO-AR (Box 31)
      Includes materials from the Art Collection Foundation
    - AS-AU (Box 31)
    - BA (Box 31)
      Includes materials on Ernie Barnes
    - BE (Box 31)
      Includes materials on Romare Bearden
    - BH-BI (Box 31)
    - BL (Box 31)
    - BO (Box 31)
      Includes materials on Sonia Boyce
    - BR (Box 31)
      Includes materials on Frederick Brown
    - BU (Box 31)
      Includes materials on Ronald Burns
    - CA (Box 31)
      Includes materials on Elizabeth Catlett
    - CE-CH (Box 31)
      Includes materials on Dana Chandler and an exhibition flyer for "The Dinner Party" signed by Judy Chicago with a dedication to Dr. Powell
    - CL (Box 31)
      Includes materials on Edward Clark
    - CO (Box 59)
      Includes materials on Renee Cox
    - CR (Box 59)
    - DA (Box 59)
    - DE (Box 59)
    - DI-DO (Box 59)
    - DR (Box 59)
      Includes materials on David Driskell
    - DU (Box 59)
      Includes materials on Robert S. Duncanson
    - EC-EM (Box 59)
    - ET-EX (Box 59)
    - FA (Box 33)
    - FE-FI (Box 33)
    - FO (Box 33)
    - FR (Box 33)
    - GA-GI (Box 33)
      Includes materials on Sam Gilliam
    - GO-GR (Box 33)
    - HA-HE (Box 33)
    - HI (Box 33)
      Includes materials on Felrath Hines
    - HO-HU (Box 33)
      Includes materials on Richard Hunt
    - IM-IR (Box 34)
    - JA-JON (Box 34)
      Includes materials on Ben Jones
    - JOS-JOU (Box 34)
    - K (Box 34)
    - LA (Box 34)
      Includes information on Jacob Lawrence
    - LE (Box 34)
    - LI (Box 34)
      Includes information on Glenn Ligon